Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited Q2 and
H1 FY24 earnings conference call. From
the senior management we have with us
today Mr. Barav Daz Gupta MD and CEO of
the company, Mr. Gopal Balachandran, CFO
and CRO, Mr. Sanjiv Mantri, executive
director and Mr. Aloc Akarwal, executive
director.
Please note that any statements,
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involves risk and
uncertainties
which could cause results to defer
materially from the current views being
expressed.
As a reminder, all participant lines
will be in the listen only mode and
there will be an opportunity for you to
ask questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star 10 on the
touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Bharkov Daz Gupta MD and CEO ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Limited. Thank
you and O to you sir. Thank you Ziko and
good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of Lombard General Insurance
Limited company for Q2 and H1 FI24.
Let me give you a brief overview of the
industry trends and developments that we
have witnessed in the past few months.
Post this our CFO Mr. Gopal Balachandran
will share the financial performance of
the company for the quarter and the half
year ended September 30, 2020.
The global economy is experiencing
experiencing a loss of momentum.
However, the Indian economy is gaining
strength led by domestic drivers such as
private consumption and fixed asset
investments by public sector capex.
The southwest monsoon rainfall recovered
during September. However, it ended
below the long period average. The
manufacturing and services PMIs and
other high frequency indicators ex
exhibited a robust expansion during this
quarter. On the demand front, urban
consumption is buoyant while rural
demand is showing some signs of revival.
However, the current geopolitical
conditions and higher interest rates in
the advanced economies can impact global
and domestic economic growth negatively
and we have to be watchful of the same
for the quarter. As per data published
by CM, the new private car sales
continue to deliver robust growth year
on year. The two-wheer sales registered
moderate growth for the quarter and in
terms of volume still remains below the
prepandemic levels. The commercial
vehicle growth was driven by growth in
infra and other core sectors. Health
insurance continued to deliver robing
the largest contributor to overall
growth. The commercial segment witnessed
growth in line with the current market
environment. We remain optimistic that
the industry will continue to grow given
the favorable macros, regulatory
changes, low penetration and relatively
positive consumer sentiment.
Speaking of the performance, the general
insurance industry delivered a GDPI
growth of 14.9% for the first half of
this year over the first half of last
year. Excluding the crop insurance, the
growth is at 18% for the same period.
Overall the underwriting performance
worsened with the combined ratio of the
industry at 113.3% for Q1 FI24 as
against 111.4 for Q1 FI2C
for motor business. While the combined
ratio continues to remain elevated the
combined ratio for the industry improved
to 120.1% from Q1 2024 as against 124.5%
for Q1 2020C.
Moving to the business numbers for us in
Q2 FI 2024 the company grew at 17.4%
as compared to the industry growth of
12.5%.
In terms of growth of key segments
during the quarter property and casualty
line of business grew at 17.2% which was
higher than the industry growth of 8.6%.
Further during the quarter we accreted
market share across all segments such as
fire, marine, engineering and liability.
In motor, our growth for the quarter was
10.9% as against the industry growth of
13.9%.
The growth in motor segment was aided by
robust growth of 27.6% in the new
private car segment. The private car mix
stands at 51.8% for the for this
quarter. While the competitive intensity
of the motor segment remained elevated,
we continue our focus of developing a
quality portfolio based on granular
data. We continue to rebalance our
portfolio resulting in commercial
vehicle mix at 22.1% and two wheeler mix
at 26.1% for quarter 2 of this year.
We also continue to harness our digital
capabilities in building claims
efficiency in motors. In Q2 FI24 through
our preferred partner network PN
network, we were able to service 63% of
our nonoem claims up from 44% in Q2 of
2023.
The health segment continues to be the
fastest growing segment for the
industry. During this quarter, we grew
at 20.3%. As a result of our continued
investment in retail health
distribution, we have grown in line with
the industry at 18.7%.
This was driven by growth in business
source to the retail health agency
vertical of 21.7%.
I would also like to share that our
one-stop solution for all insurance and
wellness needs take care app has
surpassed surpassed 6.9 million uh user
downloads till date. The incremental
download for the quarter was 1.3 million
for Q2 of FI24. The premium source
through Takeare app contributed to
884.57
million to the overall GDP reflecting a
3.5 times increase year on year.
We have been updating you about our
digital business initiatives like
digital one and I'll take care which
we've been driving in an agile manner.
We are now scaling these agile models to
business lines across the company
completely redefining the ways of
working and the business processes
coupled with the transformation of the
core system. We expect this to be a key
driver for our future growth as a
digitally empowered insurance company.
As you are all uh you may be aware I
have decided to pursue an overseas
opportunity after spending over 14.5
years with IC Lombard. It has been a
wonderful journey for me and I'm
grateful for the collective support of
all our stakeholders, our employees,
customers, channel partners, analysts
and shareholders. We have made large
strides in the industry and made a much
loved brand as India's largest private
sector GI player. I take this
opportunity to thank all of you for your
support and hope you will extend the
same support as I pass on the baiton to
my dear colleague Sanjiv Mantri.
Sanjiv has been with the IC group for
over 20 years. Sanjiv has played a
stellar stellar role in terms of his
achievement within the company. He
spearheaded the regional division as an
executive director where he was leading
distribution of products across
agencies, bank insurance, direct and
alternate channels. He was also in
charge of the strategy, products,
pricing, marketing and corporate
communication verticals at IC Lombard.
I'm convinced that IC Lumbad will
continue to be a strong force of
positive change in the industry under
his leadership. Over to you. Thank you
Bargo. Your leadership is an inspiration
for all of us and your stellar record
over the last 15 years has left an
indelible impact on the organization and
the industry at large. We are excited
for you and the opportunities that lie
ahead and wish you the very best. I'm
keenly looking forward to taking the
journey ahead and we rely heavily on the
support of all our stakeholders. These
are interesting times for the GI
industry and we are very well positioned
to capitalize on this. I look forward to
meeting and interacting with each one of
you personally. We will continue to
remain focused on our overall philosophy
of balancing growth and profitability.
I will now request Gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter and half
year. Thanks for
the question. I will now give you a
brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and half year. We have uploaded
the results presentation on our website.
You can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers. The gross
direct premium income of the company was
at rupes 124.72 billion in H1 FI24 as
against rupees 105.55 billion in H1
FI23. The growth of 18.2% as against
industry growth of 14.9%.
Excluding crop GDP of the company was at
17.6%
which was in line with industry growth
of 18% in quarter 2 FYI 24 GDP was at
rupees 60.86 86 billion in Q2 as against
51.85 million rupees in Q2 FI23 a growth
of 17.4%. This growth was higher than
the industry growth of 12.5%.
Our GDPI growth during the quarter was
primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segments. The overall GDPI of
our property and casualty segment grew
by 17.2% at 14.76 billion rupees in
quarter 2 FI24 as against rupes 12.59
billion in quarter 2 FI23.
On the retail side of the business, GDP
of the motor segment was at rupees 21.38
billion in quarter 2 FI24 as against
rupes 19.28 billion in Q2 FI23
registering a growth of 10.9%.
The advanced premium numbers was at
rupes 32.89 billion as at September 30,
2023 as against rupes 32.17 billion as
at March 31, 2023. GDP of the health
segment was at rupes 13.62 62 billion in
Q2 FI24 as against rupes 11.32 billion
in Q2 FI23 registering a growth of
20.3%.
Our agents which included the point of
sale distribution count was at 122 461
as on September 30 2023 up from around 1
lak 17,149 as on June 30, 2023. GDP of
the retail health segment grew by 19%.
Group health segment that's a corporate
employer employee segment grew by 20.6%
6% during the quarter. The bank
assurance and KRG group grew at 24.3%
this quarter. During the quarter, our
business source through our digital one
team grew at 26.7%.
Overall, our digital focus has enabled
us to increase our digital revenues
which includes the ILT care app business
to rupees 3.66 billion which accounts
for 6% of our overall GDP for the
quarter.
Re resultantly the combined ratio was
103.7% for H1 FI24 as against 104.6% for
H1 FI23
excluding the impact of CAT losses of
rupees.83 billion in H1 FI24 and
rupees.28 billion in H1 FI23. The
combined ratio was 102.7% and 104.2%
respectively. Combined ratio was 103.9%
in quarter 2 FI24 as against 105.1% in
quarter 2 FI23 excluding the impact of
calculuses of rupees48 billion in Q2
FI24 and rupes28 billion in Q2 FI23. The
combined ratio was 102.8% and 104.3%
respectively. Our investment assets rose
to rupes 453.12 billion as at September
30 2023 up from rupes 449.05 05 billion
as at June 30, 2023. Our investment
leverage net of borance was 4.07 times
as at September 30, 2023 as against 4.16
times as at June 30, 2023. Investment
income was at rupes 17.59 billion in
H124 as against rupes 13.94 billion in
H1 FI23. On a quarterly basis, the
investment income was at rupes 9.36
billion in Q2 FI24 as against rupees
7.39 billion in Q2 FI23. Our capital
gains net of impairment on investment
assets stood at rupes 2.87 billion in H1
FI24 as compared to rupees 1.43 billion
in H1 FI23. Capital gains net of
impairment on investment assets stood at
rupees 1.65 65 billion in Q2 FI24 as
compared to rupees 1.11 billion in Q2
FI23. Our profit before tax grew by
19.4% at rupees 12.84 billion in H1 FI24
as against rupees 10.75 billion in H1
FI23. Whereas CBT grew by 25.3% at
rupees 7.64 billion in Q2 FI24 as
against rupees 6.10 billion in Q2 FI23.
Consequently, profit after tax grew by
3% at rupees 9.68 billion in H1 FI24 as
against rupees 9.40 billion in H5 H1
FI23. P deg drew by 2.2% at rupees 5.77
billion in Q2 FI24 from rupees 5.91
billion in Q2 FI23.
Operator request has been initiated. If
you'd like to cancel this request,
please press star zero again. 2% in H1
FI24
and
24.8% in Q2 FI24.
Return on average equity was 18% in H1
FI24
[Music]
H1 FI23.
The ROE for quarter 2 FI 24 was 21.1%.
as against 24.5% in quarter 2 FI23 tooly
ratio was at 2.59 times as at September
30 2023 as against 2.53 times as at June
30 2023 continued to be higher than the
regulatory minimum requirement of 1.5
times. The board of directors of the
company has declared interim dividend of
rupees 5 per share for H1 FI24 as
against rupees 4.5 per share for H1
FI23.
As I conclude, I would like to reiterate
we continue to stay focused on driving
profitable growth, sustainable value
creation and safeguarding the interest
of policy holders at all times. I would
like to thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take any specific questions that you
have. Thank you. Thank you very much. We
will now begin the question and answer
session. Anyone who wishes to ask a
question may press star and one on their
touchstone telephone. If you wish to
withdraw yourself from the question
queue, you may press star and two.
Participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question. Ladies
and gentlemen, we will wait for a moment
while the question queue assembles.
Our
first question is from the line of Ain
Singh from MK Global. Please go ahead.
Yeah. Hi, good evening. Uh thanks for
the opportunity. Uh uh best wishes to
you VGO for your future endeavors and
congratulations to M Sanju on his new
role. Uh uh good set of performance.
Couple of questions. Uh first one uh I
mean uh on your motor side of course uh
you commented about the competitive
intensity uh but whatever I see
incrementally in your uh quarter two
overall motor profitability seems to be
uh quite good for you yet you remain
sort of very very guarded with the
motor. I mean so why such I would say
the guarded approach even when
profitability uh seems to be suggesting
that okay uh things are better than what
they were a few quarters back. So that
is on your entire strategy around motor
because even in motor CV you have
started to sort of uh take a bit of more
business but again there you it seems
that okay you are sort of trying to slow
down. So on overall motor I would like
to understand the philosophy and on the
same point now I guess if I understand
the regulation correctly now even motor
TP technically a commission is sort of a
possible because I mean the business
line wise uh commission caps are gone so
what is sort of a practices you are
witnessing in the market as far as motor
is concerned so that's on motor and on
health I of course I see that okay uh
the uh results are coming from your
focus on agency and that sort of leading
to sort of a growth in retail yet if I
see because you are growing uh strongly
in the group both on the banker side as
well as the employee employee
your mix is shifting again more towards
uh group I mean of course the banker is
largely retail I understand yet I'm
saying that on your individual side I
mean is that growth is still a bit you
are calibrated or why I mean uh because
on the group uh employer employee side
if I understand the price hike is now
behind so it would be largely kind of a
volume growth. So that growth is strong
da growth is strong is I mean so on the
pure retail why sort of a bit of slower
as per your own experience. So the two
questions thank you. Uh thanks and maybe
Saj can answer the question.
Yeah sure. So thanks Ainina. Uh clearly
from a motor perspective as you rightly
said there are enough and more tailwinds
available at the industry level and we
are well set to capitalize. uh in a way
in your question itself I see the answer
uh that uh we are able to drive it
profitably because we have kept
ourselves calibrated and we've also
always maintained that we will move
where we see an opportunity in terms of
profit pool uh if you look at our own uh
configuration of motor portfolio overall
you will see that the CV portfolio has
marginally gone down in terms of a
contribution in H1 of 23.4 moved to 21.6
six and we have grown on private car and
two-heer as a company. Uh if you ask me
in terms of the view the way we expect
ourselves we we would continue to exert
what is required uh but if you see
intensity which is uh in our mind not
working out overall we will probably be
a tad cautious in terms of driving edge.
So overall our plan of uh being uh
competitive and being in this place
because this is where Rashi distribution
is we will continue to exert ourselves
as a team. Uh on the health part which
you spoke about in terms of growth
coming from group health rather than
retail uh if you see our investor is
largely has been on the retail side and
there you'll see a delta over industry
growth of 2%. uh group health has always
maintained that we go in strategically.
If we see that we are able to uh see
some sanity in terms of rally we go in
deep that for in quarter one but in
quarter two if you see we have grown
rather subdued with the market uh that
plan per se for us as a company uh will
not change but our trajectory on the
retail side is far more permanent and
you will see us doing much better. there
is a marginal improvement in market
share but I would not like to read too
much into that because over a period of
time we would do uh much better and we
continue to stay invested as far as
health agency is concerned.
Yeah thank you and that question
regarding uh uh you know current
practices around commissions in motor
bas because I mean technically now I
mean one can pay commissions on motor PP
as well. So what sort of a market I mean
post the sort of you know basically the
commission caps are going to um cap what
kind of a market practices you are
seeing as far as the pre-ops are
concerned. So so Avin clearly we spoke
about the industry level numbers on
motor and we see a marginal improvement
in the overall combined ratio from 124
it moved to 120. uh frankly speaking
there's not too much you can read into
those numbers as far as this uh you know
this point of time even one on expense
of management while it does come in you
see almost 50% of the company being more
than the limit which is there which is
stated uh have we seen uh overall
rationality prevailing across uh frankly
speaking the industry itself is just
distributed at this point of time and
over a period of time I do believe that
uh you will see far more rationalization
than what's happened now and we we do
expect strategies to coming by quarter
three or quarter four overall from an
overall perspective.
Okay. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Our next question is from the
line of Shria Shivani from CLSA. Please
go ahead.
Yes. Uh thank you for the opportunity
and congratulation on a good set of
numbers. Uh so so on the coming back on
the motor book I uh wanted some more
understanding on uh the loss ratio
improvement that has happened in 1
versus 1Q. Uh I know you don't want us
to look us on look at loss ratios on
quarterly basis but if even even the 1
numbers look quite good. So that would
be one question. Uh second is on the uh
monthly performance. So uh while I
understand your monthly performances do
vary but if you can give us some color
in uh understanding what specifically
happened in probably August and
September because till July you guys
were had a very strong run rate of about
20%. So uh any color now around what
happened and uh any growth outlook that
you can uh give and so one more question
third question probably uh you've
launched a new product with ICI brew
life the health and protection product
uh management mentioned in the
conference call yesterday so if you can
give us some understanding of the
economics of such a product you know uh
premiums uh the way uh uh partnership
with IC pro works out I'm assuming this
will get sold on the IC bag platform so
some color on
So, so Sh uh I think on the first one I
think if you look at uh uh on the loss
ratios for motor um I think you're
right. I think we keep saying that you
should never look at numbers uh over
quarters or even let's say even on a
financial year basis because some of
these lines will obviously kind of start
to exhibit outcomes over a relatively
longer period of time particularly in
the context of motor third party. uh
having said that I think when you look
at even for let's say the half year uh
on motor specifically in general what we
have talked about is the portfolio loss
ratio should kind of range between the
65 to 70% kind of threshold on motor own
damage uh for the half year I think that
number is at let's say 65% or
thereabouts but that's a range at which
you would possibly see depending on what
kind of a business mix that we write in
terms of whether we are able to
relatively pick up pick up a higher
proportion of uh new or let's say
relatively what kind of proportion are
we able to write in the context of the
older portfolio. So that's broadly the
range at which we will be able to
operate at within quarters obviously the
loss ratios will undergo a change but
that's the range that we are comfortable
with in so far as uh the own damage book
is concerned on third party again the
point is still the same I think while
for the quarter you would have again
seen the number slightly better or let's
say even on a half yearly basis uh I
think number stands at about 66%. But
these are experiences that one should
logically again look at uh over
relatively longer periods uh and also to
the fact that depending on what kind of
a mix of business that we ride in terms
of private car two-heer and CV and
that's something that we keep
calibrating from time to time
corresponding to which you could
possibly see a change in the uh loss
ratio uh experience uh but otherwise
there's nothing specific to call out in
the context of let's say uh the uh
quarter two numbers
Having said that, I think what we also
keep doing is given the fact that from a
reserving perspective, generally we have
tried to be prudent at all points of
time. That philosophy still continues to
remain the same. Uh even as we write
whichever portfolio of the book but over
a period of time as you would have seen
some of our experiences have actually
started to turn out to be much much
positive than let's say what our initial
estimates have been. So that will
obviously get calibrated from time to
time. But otherwise in so far as the
overall portfolio is concerned it's
purely a function of what kind of mixes
mix of business that that we're able to
write. Just to add to a point that Gopal
made is that uh the way we look at
businesses on a combined basis not just
loss ratio and overall you should study
our numbers on a combined perspective
where certain businesses may have higher
expenses uh you know lower loss ratio
and vice versa. So as a we as a team we
look at overall combined as a as an
object over to you for the for this uh
combo product that got mentioned. Yes,
we really excited. We have uh taken the
term and the uh CHR product of ours and
given a combo combined offering to our
customers through our agency channel. Uh
if you look at it PU has a very decent
agency practice and we have very decent
bankration practice and there was uh a
gap which needed to be filled. We have
uh created this product line to you know
leverage on each other's distribution
and as per the regulatory environment
that is there. It's something which is a
very feasible option. We have gone ahead
and done this uh partnership with them
and we expect this product to fully ramp
up in time to come. Uh to be very honest
our agents will require a bit of a
training and process. it will come with
a lagu over a period of time but but
that being said we are really excited
with this partnership that we have done
with them to drive uh the combo product
in the market which in many ways is
first of its kind and to your last
question Shria on the monthly
performance numbers again I think that's
purely a function of uh what kind of
businesses do we write between periods
uh as we had explained even in the
earlier call our business do tend to
have a bit of cyclicality across of
businesses. Uh so for example in quarter
one you will obviously see a relatively
higher proportion of some of the
commercial lines being underwritten. In
quarter two we do see businesses booked
particularly in the context of crop. Now
that could get booked in a in a
particular month and therefore to that
extent you may possibly see variations
in growth percentages when you look at
it relatively on a month-on-month basis.
But here again as we keep saying I think
a better way to look at given the
cyclicality of the business that we get
get to see and maybe for example quarter
three you will see a lot more business
largely driven through let's say some of
the retail growth uh so again you may
see let's say month-on-month changes
between segments of businesses u but
however when you look at it on a full
year basis I think in line with what we
have spoken uh largely looking at way
looking at the way how how things are
positively shaping up for us uh we
should definitely look at ending the
year within that high teens percentage
growth that we have talked about and uh
in general I mean depending on what
Sanji also mentioned uh on the expense
of management side I think if things
starts to get uh improved much better
from an industry perspective then the
relative outperformance that we have
talked about of 100 200 basis point over
and above the market growth rate that's
something that we still believe we'll be
able to achieve
got it sir thank you this answers my
question thank you
thank you
our next question is from the line of
Nidesh from Invest. Please go ahead.
Uh thanks for the opportunity. uh uh
what is the share of OEM and nonMe
business in the motor and how it has
been conducted over last two years
overall if you see in our split in terms
of the motor that we speaking about we
would almost have 70% out of our
business coming uh from the OEM business
and the rest would be coming through
other channels which agency and bank
insurance
sure I think last year we articulated
ated our intention to move towards uh to
increase the share of non OEM uh by
focusing on high loss ratio low low
expense ratio uh uh business uh so how
is the progress on that has a share of
non going up so uh overall if you see
again uh uh incrementally yes we intend
exercising ourselves more on the agency
side but uh the manner in which a motor
book has got created uh there's a fair
amount of contribution and if we see an
opport opportunity is there. It's not
one for the other. We'll continue to
invest extensively on the agency
business side. But that being said, OEM
where we've been working for years and
we built a franchise, we will continue
to drive that. Uh so we need to look at
both of both of these in a
um there are times where OEM
contribution can go really up. I mean I
mean there's a season coming in quarter
three. Obviously you'll find again OEM
you know uh probably showing a larger
percentage. But that being said, agency
business should continue to do well. Uh
but relatively to put percentage pool
would be a very uh difficult option.
It's not one for the other. So n just to
add to what Sanjit said uh I think
strategically and philosophically while
we are investing there will be times
when OEM will again come back up right.
So if new vehicle sales increase as has
happened I as we said in the opening
remarks uh I think the share of new
vehicle has been very positive for us
and those are profitable pools. So when
we see those opportunities we want to
guard it.
Sure. Understood. Understood. Secondly I
noticed that there is some change in the
senior management personnel uh
structure. uh so uh if you can explain
what is the requirement for that and uh
what is uh uh this emerging market uh
group uh if you can share some details
on that emerging markets group so
effectively it's a very minor change
it's not a significant change but we
have an experienced resource which has
joined in and he's an expert in terms of
driving the emerging market so we have
pulled him in to report into uh Aloh
which otherwise had a multiple reporting
so we want to use the benefit of his
presence in the system.
And emerging market group is a is a
commercial lines or emerging market
uh operates across uh channels and
business lines. Basically this is the
you know bhat rather than in the top
cities right. So this is where if you
remember last year we had done a little
bit of uh you know structuring change
where logar was a looking after of a
wholesale business was given specific
focus or given charge of that that
market with specific focus and we are
investing and we are growing that
business. Uh so typically let's say the
top 40 cities would be not there but
thereafter it would be considered to be
emerging.
Sure. Sure. Thank you. Uh that's it from
my side. Thank you. Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, in order to ensure
that the management is able to address
questions from all participants in the
conference, please limit your questions
to one or two for participants. Should
you have a follow-up question, we would
request you to rejoin the queue. Thank
you. Our next question is from the line
of trank kora from Evendis Park. Please
go ahead. Yeah. Uh thank you. Thank you
for the opportunity. Uh uh my my first
question is that whether you want to
pre-pone your guidance of 102.5
to be achieved because because x of cm
of 55 you are almost there uh uh what
what we have thought we will achieve it
by exit of fi25. So I just wanted to
understand uh whether whether uh given
given the underwriting environment you
believe that could happen little uh
quicker than expected that's point
number one and and second within within
the uh this 102.5 or combined ratio
improvement uh mean the some some
weightage was expected to come from the
OPEX part but despite EOM um our opex
compared to last year still still has
been higher or or in one also it's
higher so I just wanted to understand
that EOM is overall dragging the opex
low higher or or increasing the opex on
the higher side or or you believe sanity
will come and will expense ratios will
improve for the sector as
sanit
right you just you're delivering better
than expected numbers and that's what we
want to continue to do uh no change in
guidance as you know the market is still
very competitive we've talked about
where the combined issue for the
industry is in terms of motor share moto
segment uh but clearly I over the last
one year the team has done a brilliant
job in terms of uh uh you know
significantly calibrating uh the
business as also building a lot of
capability on the cost side both on the
claims and and expense side uh so I
think you know we the team is doing
really well but there's no need to
change guidance as we see it at this
point in time on the cost side I'll ask
Gopal to answer yeah so I think we will
we'll still continue to maintain what we
have been kind of talking work which is
uh I think the businesses has always
have to be looked at as what Bargo also
just mentioned in response to the
earlier one which is we always look at
the businesses from an overall combined
perspective uh because different
businesses would obviously have a mix of
let's say loss experience and let's say
the expense ratios as well. uh just to
kind of uh uh look at the overall
expense of management specifically to
answer your point uh first half of last
year our expense of management was at
27.3
relative to that if you look at our
first half of this year we are at about
26.9 uh so hence to that extent even
from an EOM perspective we have actually
seen a marginal improvement in line with
what we definitely wanted to kind of
drive it towards and this is despite the
fact that we continue to make our
investments in those areas of building
distribution on health agency technology
some of the core transformation project
that we talked about. I think clearly we
would want to continue to make those
investments and hence to that extent you
may not suddenly see a big shift
happening in so far as specifically in
the context of the expense ratio numbers
are concerned. we will obviously drive
uh a a positive change but having said
that I think we will directionally be
more guided by the other objective that
we have specifically spelt out which got
reiterated as we speak which is a
combined ratio objective of 102% is
something that we want to achieve by the
end of next year so that's something
that we want to clear it live and as I
said purely uh the breakdown of expense
is a function of loss and expenses got
it got one one just last two questions
or or one question which is one data
keeping typical loss ratio of retail
health and group health uh that that if
you can share and second I just just
wanted to understand this IL take care
6% of GWP is is a big big achievement so
so um how do you see this to be
contributing and and and if you can give
a color how much is mixed driven by
motor and helping in Iotecha
so so the number of 6% is the digital
contribution uh some case the second
point second part of your question uh so
therefore to that extent that also
includes let's say the business that we
source through takeare app and as we
have been talking about I think
consistently whether you look at it on a
year-on-year basis obviously there is a
multiplier increase in so far as the
premium that we are sourcing through I
take care is concerned roughly about 3.7
times increase that we have seen uh but
even when you look at it on a sequential
basis I think we have been able to kind
of uh grow the contributions coming into
that particular uh particular app so we
are very very excited with the way how
things are getting played And equally we
are getting to see a lot more uh product
per customer in so far as the use of the
app is concerned and that will continue
to drive both uh volumes as well as
let's say value of premium in so far as
a digital contribution is concerned. uh
to your first point in so far as the
breakdown of the loss ratios are
concerned I think for quarter two uh the
breakdown of the overall health loss
ratios into corporate health and retail
indemnity corporate health loss ratios
are at about 102%. And the retail health
indemnity loss ratios are 66.6%.
Now this number I think when the numbers
that we gave out for quarter 1 last year
corporate health was about 92.6 and the
retail health indivity numbers were
64.2. Now obviously these numbers have
to be looked at in the context of how do
we see some of the loss incidences play
out. I mean particularly in quarter two
we do get to see a slight increase in
loss incidents primarily because
typically it's a monsoon season and we
get to see a lot more increase in uh
health related ailments that we get to
see and this is not specifically only
for this particular quarter two even
otherwise when you look at it even for
the last year for example clearly we had
seen an increase in the loss ratios
playing out between let's say a quarter
two versus a quarter one so hence in
that sense I think we are pretty much
okay with the way how the loss
experiences is playing out and as we had
indicated in so far as the portfolio
growth is concerned I think it is coming
at a price at which we are comfortable
with and uh in the subsequent quarters
we should start seeing some of these
loss ratios getting normalized
particularly in the context of lowering
down of loss incidences that we see in
Q3 and Q4 just to supplement what Gopal
said you know and we've talked about
this in the past the entire thought
process uh and the and the approach
behind I take care was uh consumer
engagement right engaging with our
customers be it you know uh the employer
employee segment where the individual is
a potential retail customer or our
retail customer B2C customer who comes
on board and uh and the approach that we
are taking is that as we have more
engaged customers they will renew better
you will have cross-ell opportunities
and hopefully the relationship will be
more sticky so principally for us
whatever business we get as long as it's
viable We are not driving motor numbers
or health numbers there. It's a customer
engagement app and uh and and as an
organization we don't want to split that
number at this point in time to say okay
this is my motor number this is my
health number because it might drive us
in a manner which is not
customercentric. Uh so uh so as an
organization we've been giving the
numbers in ter number of app downloads
the total volume of crossell and and
upsell business that we are doing which
is something that we continue to. Thank
you. Sorry to interrupt Mr. Sanil Koda.
May we request that you return to the
question queue for follow-up questions
as there are several participants
waiting for their turn. Thank you sir.
Our next question is from the line of
Swarnab Mukhar G from BNK securities.
Please go ahead.
Hi sir thank you for the opportunity and
congress on a good set of numbers. So
I'll again come back to u you know the
motor loss ratios. So uh hey I
understand that what you have
articulated in terms of uh your
experience uh and maybe some releases
that are coming uh but just you know for
a view of how the loss ratios are going
to pan out uh I mean say in mot
uh your loss ratios have been little bit
fluctuating over quarters. Uh right now
that there has been a bit of a
improvement going ahead. If you can give
some color on the full year how we
should think about this number where it
can sustain uh same for OD given that uh
you you are picking up on growth uh on
the uh OD business and particularly
private people in the mix how confident
would you be in kind of maintaining this
kind of loss ratio. So that is the first
one and uh secondly uh in terms of the
investment income I just wanted to
understand the yield that you have shown
uh realized return is uh fairly strong I
think slightly higher than what we have
done in the past. So is there certain uh
you know tactical bets that have you
know that have worked out which might
not play out in the coming quarters. uh
so and what kind of we can think about
for the you know going ahead on a
normalized basis that's so for on the
first one I think uh which is what I
kind of responded uh to the earlier one
uh and one had kind of talked about the
range at which we would be comfortable
so one I think when we look at motor as
a line of business we obviously look at
it again more from a combined
perspective which will be a combination
of both the loss experience and let's
say the expense ratios and As what we
just discussed again it will depend on
what proportion of new business that we
write because new typically comes with a
relatively better loss experience and
correspondingly let's say the expense
ratios could slightly stay elevated and
correspondingly let's say the older
portfolios as we just discussed
typically comes with a slightly high LR
and let's say a relatively lower cost of
distribution. So honestly that will be a
interplay that one one would get to see
in so far as writing this book is
concerned. But having said that I think
the range at which one would be
comfortable to operate in the context of
motor loan damage is what I kind of
responded earlier which is in the range
of between 65 to 70%. depending on what
kind of a business mix that we write in
the in in respect of proportion of uh uh
new or let's say the relatively older
portfolio on third party again pretty
much we have kind of talked about that's
what I responded obviously we should
again not look at these numbers uh
particularly for quarters or let's say
even on a half yearly basis uh you have
to look at the numbers over relatively
longer period uh so there again it will
be a function of what uh kind of uh loss
experiences that one sees
But broadly I would say that one could
see the third party loss ratios again
kind of hovering around what you see on
a full year basis that would be largely
representative of the range at which we
would get to see the loss ratio play
out. So that's the response uh to your
first one uh to your second one on the
overall uh investment book. uh I think
uh in fact in the past quarters people
have been asking us why have we not seen
let's say so much of an increase in the
overall uh interest income of the
portfolio. uh now if you recollect I
think what we generally do is u
depending on the market opportunity that
one sees is how we place our overall
portfolio at and for example we tend to
kind of in this high interest rate uh
environment we obviously want to
capitalize the opportunity that one sees
and so far as uh acrual to the book is
concerned and which is why our overall
uh duration of the book in fact stands
at about 5.23 23 years. This number if I
remember it correctly uh at the end of
the at the beginning of the year uh was
at about 4.99 years. So obviously we
have gone a bit long and we have kind of
rightly positioned the portfolio in
order to capitalize as I said the
increased uh uh interest rates that one
sees in the market. Uh so hence to that
extent we will obviously get to see this
kind of play out even as we kind of head
into the subsequent quarters. What is it
that you may not necessarily see playing
out over the subsequent periods is
purely a function of the extent of
capital gains that one sees in the
market that's purely driven by let's say
the market opportunity that one sees and
even in the past we've talked about it
uh between quarters you can always see
fluctuations in the break up of the
overall investment income uh depending
on how market plays out is what you will
be able to see some kind of gain playing
out so so hence to answer your point I
think uh the way we are positioned the
portfolio is what is helping us in terms
of capitalizing the uh increased uh uh
interest uh income
and just to just to supplement the point
that Gopal made uh uh and we've been
talking about this that our uh carry
yield will increase and GPA's given this
number if you also look at the split of
the unrealized gains the unrealized gain
and the equity book has increased uh at
the end of this quarter uh obviously on
the debt side and the bond side has come
down because interest rates have gone
gone up but that is not something that
we worried about because these are all
uh calls that we've taken to stay long
in uh in the dead market. That's how our
has increased.
Understood sir. Yeah. Thank you so much
and all the best. Thank thanks.
Thank you. Our next question is from the
line of Rishi Junjunwala from IFL
Institutional Equities. Please go ahead.
Yeah, thanks for the opportunity. Just a
couple of questions. Uh uh firstly, you
know, this September month would have
seen the first 5year anniversary of the
two-wheeler long-term TP. Um so how has
the experience been in terms of renewal?
This is you know given that 5 years of
TP means that the renewals are pretty
much down to zero and and as a result uh
you know if you can give some color in
terms of what would you know that amount
of premium for September month be as per
portion of overall motor TP.
So uh uh thanks Ishi. Uh clearly yes
this was the first month uh
overarchingly if you ask me overall the
industry level there's a good reason why
I think Supreme Court get the bug in
terms of having long-term risk. Uh the
retention rates uh continue to be
relatively on the lower side. I would
not speak in terms of the amount but
retention levels that we have seen as a
team right now is around 15 to 20%. uh
the development of this uh will happen
over uh you know summation of probably a
quarter in terms of what are the true
numbers because we'll have to pursue
this uh uh with our own customers and
see where we end up losing it. uh but
it's but it's something as a pool that
we are very keen so we're using all
possible analytics to see if we can
further sharpen our X and see that uh we
can guide these numbers uh even if it's
only TP we'll be more than happy to
write this pool
understood and the second is uh just on
the total payouts to the distribution uh
channels um you know some of our uh life
insurance peers have talked about u you
know industrywide increase in payout
outs uh to the distribution channels. Um
how has it behaved uh for us uh in the
the key banka partner channel as well as
outside of that uh in terms of the total
payout? I understand there was you know
uh you know categorization or
reclassification but just in terms of
payout has there been uh demand for
increase in payouts for us and uh have
you seen any kind of anomalies in the
industry otherwise? So uh overall if you
see for us as a company expense of
management has stayed within the range
uh and in fact it's come down uh from a
27.3 to 26.9. Uh so frankly speaking uh
there is no accelerated increase but in
certain pockets where we have seen a bit
of an acceleration you see that
dynamically we will go again to what our
basic thesis has been. we will see where
we can get viable business uh in terms
of acquiring it. Uh in a way to some
extent you can see our motor market
share also is reflecting that we had a
calibrated growth uh to probably
maintain profitability over just uh
market share growth. So you can read in
terms of what's happening overarchingly
uh but overall we seem to be in control
uh at this point of time.
Okay. Thank you so much. Yeah. Thanks.
Thank you. Our next question is from the
line of Pra Jen from Motilwal. Please go
ahead.
Mr. Pra Jen, your line has been unmuted.
You can go ahead. Yeah. Hi. Hi.
Congratulations on set of numbers. Uh
firstly, uh you know uh I just missed
the agency count number. Can you just
repeat?
It's about 1 lakh 22,000 which includes
the agency that includes the point of
sale distribution as well. So this was
it is 1 lakh 22,000 this number at the
end of uh uh earlier period was about 1
one lakh 13,000.
Okay. Okay. And just on the you know
previous question uh sorry to interrupt
Mr. Pen may we request you to use your
answer please as your audio is muffled
sir. Thank you. Is this better?
Hello. Hello. Your voice is slightly
more feeble. Uh P, we can't hear you
clearly.
Sorry, I'll come back in the queue.
Sorry. Thank you, sir.
Our next question is from the line of
Madukar Lada from Noama Wealth
Management. Please go ahead. Hi. Uh good
evening and congratulations on a good
set of numbers. Uh couple of questions.
uh one we seeing a good increase in the
crop business uh that you're doing this
year. What is the philosophy
uh behind that? Uh I remember in the
past you wanted to avoid that business
and uh I I also know that you got this
business again from Bharti. Uh so is
that only those states or are you also
growing some of the other states? Uh so
that's that's one. Second uh again I'm
just going back to the guidance of 102%.
Given that your performance is uh quite
strong you know in first half itself you
are at 102.7.
So uh uh are you being a little bit too
conservative
over here? Um and finally um you know
most of the industry is uh ahead uh or
sorry is not meeting the uh EOM uh norms
right now. Um you know so what
regulatory action can we expect and and
what would you say uh by when uh will
the regulators start looking at this and
implementing this?
Thanks Maduk. Let me answer it in the
same uh sequence. One on crop there is
no change in philosophy as Gopal had
explained that I think Sanjiv explained
that there are certain months where you
book a premium it just shows up in that
quarter. Uh in aggregate our share of
crop business which we had guided the
market was to be was would be around 5%
of total business uh for the annual uh
business not on a quarterly basis and I
think we'll stay at at that kind of
range. we are not significantly growing
our crop book. uh in spite of the fact
that we believe some players in the
market are trying to do that because of
the advantage that they get on uh EUM
but philosophically we don't believe
that's the right strategy right approach
so we are not doing that uh uh there was
some amount of booking in the curry
season because most of the business for
us is uh in the current market period so
it's it's a bit higher in this quarter
that's about all secondly most of the
crop that we've got is in the 80 110
model uh so it's a reasonably
well-contained uh business and our
experience in the last couple of years
has been very reasonably positive on the
approach that we've had.
In terms of your question on uh uh the
combined issue coming to the question on
combined nothing more to add uh you know
whether we are being conservative that's
your call you you'll take your own views
about whether we being combin
conservative I think as I said the
guidance should remain the same if you
can outperform all of you should be
happy uh third in terms of the
regulatory action uh look it's not for
us to talk about what the regulator will
do uh But uh at least we uh hope and we
think that this time the regulator is
very serious about this. Uh at the same
time this is not about a quarterly
number that they're monitoring. They
will moni they've given a leeway for a
company on an annual basis. Uh and my my
sense is that the end of the year
they'll look at who is improved and
who's not improved and who gone beyond
uh 30%.
uh so I think it would be wise for most
companies which are already running at
higher than that number I think it would
be wise for them to bring it under
control but as I said it's not for us to
talk about what the regulatory will do
that's a question that uh in a sense you
time will give us the answer and you'll
see what the regulator does thanks just
a follow up on this are we seeing a
heightened comparative intensity in the
group health uh segment also uh to sort
of uh meet the year norms. I think GoPal
answered that and you know in the first
quarter we saw the market on group
health to be better and we had a much
higher share. Uh this quarter we've seen
some amount of uh aggression and in fact
we've seen some otherwise sensible
companies buy very large chunky groups
of businesses. Our senses is probably to
manage the expense of management. But at
the end of the day, business is not just
about expense of management. Business is
about combined, right? So you to do it
in a manner which is sensible. So uh
we'll be watchful uh and we'll see what
what happens. But overall at this point
in time, we are quite comfortable with
the group health business that we
got it. Uh thank you and all the best.
Thank you. Our next question is from the
line of Nishin Chawati from Kotak
Institutional Equities. Please go ahead.
Uh thanks for taking my question. Uh
just a small one. Uh you know when I
look at the monthly uh you know monthly
figures for motor TP business. I was
just curious that uh you know did you do
any transaction in the last month uh you
know just as something that you had done
probably in the Feb or March month last
year. No issues. We've not done any
transaction.
Perfect. Thanks. That answers my
question. Thank you.
Thank you.
Our next question is from the line of
Supratim Duta from Ambit Capital. Please
go ahead.
Thanks for the opportunity. Uh just
wanted to understand a few things. So
one the 0.48 48 billion of you know NAT
losses. Which lines of business are
those attributed to?
I think it's been largely so this
quarter uh has been largely let's say
relatively retail. Uh so we have had a
higher proportion of losses coming in
from the motor line of business but
equally we have also had some amount of
claims coming in on the property side
unlike water one where relatively the uh
losses of roughly about 35 crores which
was the cat losses in Q1 that was
largely property heavy as compared to
motor.
Got it. and uh within so if I adjust for
that NASCAT losses then in the motor OD
line then that would result in the loss
ratio being lower than 60%. Is that a
correct assumption and then my followup
question to that is you know how
sustainable is this loss ratio going
forward?
Uh so uh I had kind of already responded
to that but just to kind of reiterate u
again and we will keep saying this and
you'll get to hear us sometime and again
you should never look at quarterly
numbers uh and largely it is better to
look at numbers more on an yearly basis.
Um just to kind of reiterate on motor
own damage I think the loss ratio
depending on the kind of mix of business
that we write in motor we are
comfortable at a loss ratio range
between 65 to 70%. Uh that's a range
depending on what kind of business mix
of business we write and on TP again
it's better to kind of look at more
annual numbers uh which is largely
reflective of the loss ratio range that
one would be comfortable writing. So
hence to that extent whether you adjust
it for quarter to losses from CAD in the
loss ratios but if you do that on a
simple basis then obviously yes the loss
ratio will definitely look better than
what the reported numbers are but having
said that I think the range at which we
are comfortable at is between 65 to uh
70%. And what equally we need to
remember is that whatever be the amount
of losses I think we do have appropriate
reinsurance support such that uh if
there is a very large uh cash event
having an impact on the net that gets
appropriately protected through
necessary reinsurance arrangement.
Got it. And just one last question. So
on the fire side there has been a
slowdown in the second quarter. So just
wanted to understand how much of this is
due to the IIG burn rate being removed
uh versus you know overall competition
or you know you wanting to not write
some kind of business. just wanted. So
on that the experience what we discussed
at the end of in the first quarter is
the same which is at roughly about 56%
reduction from the earlier days which is
uh better than what we had actually we
had anticipated at the beginning of the
year. We'll have to see if this holds in
terms of fire. There are you know maybe
one or two large policies that have got
moved from period to per you know uh you
know and there's some uh you know uh
policies which you have earlier booked
in this period which may have got moved
somewhere else. So you should look at
the numbers uh with a longer uh period
rather than just a quarter. The only
thing just to add to that I think having
said that I think if you look at uh
across segments on the commercial lines
I think we still continue to outperform
the market. I think we continue to
accrete market share uh in fire as a
line of business or whether you take any
of the other commercial lines we
continue to outgrow the market. Got it.
Uh thank you. That's very helpful. Okay.
Thank you ladies and gentlemen. Due to
time constraint that was the last
question of our question and answer
session. I would now like to hand the
conference over to Mr. Bharov Daz Gupta
for closing comments.
Uh thank you. Thank you everyone. Uh I
think all of you have been great support
to uh to the company and me personally
and I really want to take this
opportunity to thank all of you for
being uh great analysts and and
investors in our company. U as I said
earlier uh I'm hoping that you'll
continue to engage with us as you have
in the past and San Frani wants to have
the last word.
No, I think absolute pleasure and uh
really keen to interact with each one of
you personally as and when uh uh your
schedule permits. Uh nothing much to add
but absolutely in agreement with Bav
that uh we've had you know great inputs
and discussions with all of you and that
continues. Uh thank you so much and
let's meet up soon. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. On behalf of
ICICI, Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited, that concludes this conference.
Thank you for joining us and you may now
disconnect your lines.